American Locomotive Company (ALCO) Records
American Locomotive Company (ALCO) Records
1872-1969
American Locomotive Company.
165 linear ft.
The American Locomotive Company was incorporated in 1901, the result of the merger of the Schenectady Locomotive Engine Manufactory with seven small companies. In 1955 it became Alco Products, Inc. and was acquired in 1964 by the Worthington Corporation. In addition to steam and diesel engines and generators, the American Locomotive Company also manufactured high quality steel and military tanks, with unsuccessful ventures in automobile manufacture (1905-1913) and the production of nuclear energy (1954-1962). Collection contains advertising and publicity, correspondence, financial records (annual reports, ledgers, etc.), technical drawings and technical manuals, maps, news clippings, personnel records, photographs, sketches and drawings, and more.
148810
Biographical History
The American Locomotive Company was incorporated in 1901 by merging 7 small locomotive companies with the Schenectady Locomotive Engine Manufactory (incorprated 1848). At its height, ALCO had headquarters in New York City and a main plant in Schenectady, New York, with other plants in Auburn and Dunkirk, New York, and Latrobe, Pennsylvania. ALCO's Schenectady facilities had affiliations with General Electric Company there. In 1955, the company changed its name to Alco Products, Incorporated. In 1964, the Worthington Corporation acquired Alco and changed its name to Citadel Industries.
Alco's main products were steam locomotives, diesel-electric locomotives, diesel engines and generators, specialized forgings, high-quality steel, and armed tanks. Alco also made some short-lived ventures into automobiles and nuclear energy in the early days of those industries.
Scope and Contents of the Collection
The American Locomotive Company (ALCO) Records comprise 7 series: General files, Financial material, Published material, Bound material, Miscellaneous, Display material, and Ledgers. Of special interest are the ventures Alco made in 1905-1913 during the early days of the automobile (see Box 30 and Ledgers), and in 1954-1962 into the fledgling field of nuclear energy (see Boxes 18-20, 32, and Oversize 12).
General files comprise material pertaining to advertising, deeds, designs, exhibits, finance, general, historical, international, locomotives, maps, news clippings, news releases, nuclear energy, ordnance, personnel, photographs, products, publicity reprints, special projects, speeches, taxes, and warehouses.
Financial material contains mostly tax and depreciation papers from 1901 through 1960.
In the Published material are Annual Reports from 1902 through 1964, and various forms of publicity, including press kits, promotional pamphlets, and periodicals.
Bound material comprises mostly technical and administrative manuals.
Miscellaneous material includes memorabilia, an index to Alco equipment in the field, two copies of an Alco products film, two phonodiscs, and two scrapbooks.
Display material contains designs, sketches and photographs.
More than 300 Ledgers comprise records of not only the American Locomotive Company, but also some smaller and earlier companies, which Alco acquired.
Arrangement of the Collection
The collection is largely in original order. For this reason, related material is not always located together. For example, publicity may be found in General files (news releases, news clippings, publicity reprints, speeches), Published material (press kits, promotional pamphlets), and Miscellaneous (scrapbooks). The researcher is advised to review the entire finding aid to ensure locating all relevant materials.
Boxes 69 and 70 (original shipping containers for films) no longer exist.
Related Material
See also the
Perry Egbert Papers
and the
Alco Collection
.
Subject and Genre Headings
Business and Industry; New York State; ALCO.; Alco Products, Incorporated.; American Locomotive Automobile Company.; American Locomotive Company.; Schenectady Locomotive Engine Manufactory.; Worthington Corporation.; Business.; Diesel locomotives -- Design and construction.; Diesel locomotives -- Maintenance and repair -- Handbooks, manuals, etc.; Diesel motor.; Locomotive industry -- United States.; Locomotive industry -- Management.; Locomotive works -- United States.; Locomotives -- Design and construction.; Locomotives -- Maintenance and repair -- Handbooks, manuals, etc.; Nuclear energy.; Nuclear locomotives.; Tanks (Military science) -- Photographs.; Manufacturers -- United States.; 35mm (photographic film size); Advertisements.; Annual reports.; Clippings (information artifacts); Correspondence.; Deeds.; Financial records.; Ledgers (account books); Long-playing records.; Manuals (instructional materials); Maps (documents); News releases.; Pamphlets.; Personnel records.; Phonograph records.; Photographs.; Scrapbooks.; Sound recordings.; Speeches (documents); Business.; Transportation.
Access Restrictions
The majority of our archival and manuscript collections are housed offsite and require advanced notice for retrieval. Researchers are encouraged to contact us in advance concerning the collection material they wish to access for their research.
Acquisition Information
Gift of Alco Products, Inc., 1968-1971.
Inventory
- General files
  - Advertising
    - Dunkirk Open House (Box 1)
    - Old Advertisements (Box 1)
    - Public Relations Memorandum, 1942 (Box 1)
    - Advertising Reprints
      - Alcotwin Heat Exchanger, 4 folders (Box 1)
      - Big Squeeze-High Quality Steel (Box 1)
      - Defense Against Corrosion (Box 1)
      - Diesel Engines, 27 folders (Box 1)
      - Feedwater Heaters, 3 folders (Box 1)
      - Finned Tubes, 2 folders (Box 1)
      - Forged Flanges, 3 folders (Box 1)
      - Forgings, 6 folders (Box 1)
      - Gate-Valves, 3 folders (Box 1)
      - Gear-Blanks, 2 folders (Box 1)
      - High-Pressure Heaters (Box 1)
      - Hi - Qua - Led Steel, 9 folders (Box 1)
      - Leaded Steels (Box 1)
      - Locomotives, 16 folders (Box 1)
      - Springs, 6 folders (Box 1)
      - Steel Pipe, 2 folders (Box 1)
      - Transportation (Box 1)
      - Tug (Box 1)
      - Type "D" Closure (Box 1)
      - Valves (Box 1)
      - Wellhead Equipment (Box 1)
    - Foreign Deliveries
      - Miscellaneous, 2 folders (Box 1)
      - Andes (Box 1)
      - Argentina, 3 folders (Box 1)
      - Brazil (Box 1)
      - Britain (Box 1)
      - India, 4 folders (Box 1)
      - Pakistan, 4 folders (Box 1)
      - Sahara, 2 folders (Box 1)
    - Advertisements
      - Business Week Merchandizer, 1959 (Box 1)
      - An Immediate Solution, 1960; 5 folders (Box 1)
      - Gable Address: Locomotive, New York, 1960 (Box 1)
      - Miscellaneous, 1961 (Box 1)
      - Alcolid, 1961 (Box 1)
      - Blue Book, 1961 (Box 2)
      - Boston Herald, 1961 (Box 2)
      - Hard Site, 1961 (Box 2)
      - AL - 8, 1962; 2 folders (Box 2)
      - Club Ad, 1962 (Box 2)
      - Wall Street Journal, 1962; 2 folders (Box 2)
      - Miscellaneous, 14 folders (Box 2)
  - Deeds
    - Auburn, 55 folders (Box 2)
    - Beaumont, 2 folders (Box 2)
    - Chicago, 2 folders (Box 2)
    - Dunkirk, 3 folders (Box 2)
    - Houma, Louisiana (Box 2)
    - Houston, Texas (Box 2)
    - Latrobe (Box 2)
    - North Bergen (Box 2)
    - St. Louis (Box 2)
    - Schenectady, 52 folders (Box 2)
    - Schenectady, 77 folders (Box 3)
    - Auburn, 1937-1947 (Box 3)
    - Houston, Texas (Box 3)
    - Niskayuna Property, Schenectady, 2 folders (Box 3)
    - St. Louis, 1959-1965 (Box 3)
    - Schenectady
      - Miscellaneous undated, 2 folders (Box 3)
      - [General], 1909-1910; 1914,; 1917-1924; 5 folders (Box 3)
      - [General], 1921-1962; 9 folders (Box 4)
    - Dead File (Box 4)
    - Indexes, 2 folders (Box 4)
    - Void Documents (Box 4)
    - Miscellaneous, 3 folders (Box 4)
    - Miscellaneous, 8 folders (Box 5)
  - Designs
    - Generators (Box 5)
    - Designs and Sketches, 3 folders (Box 5)
  - Exhibits
    - Annual Meeting, 1962 (Box 5)
    - Ceremonies
      - Atlantic Coast Line Delivery Ceremonies (Box 5)
      - Chicago Heights Plant, 50th Anniversary, 2 folders (Box 5)
      - Pakistan-200th Locomotive Exported (Box 5)
    - Export Award, 6 folders (Box 5)
    - Product Showings
      - American Railway Progress Exposition (Box 5)
      - Century 628 Locomotive, 1964 (Box 5)
      - Waldorf Show (Box 5)
    - Tours
      - Attorney General Louis Lefkowitz, 1962 (Box 5)
      - Scandinavian Engineers, 1962 (Box 5)
  - Finance
    - Annual and Quarterly Reports, 1948-1953; 13 folders (Box 6)
    - Annual and Quarterly Reports, 1959; 3 folders (Box 6)
    - Annual and Quarterly Reports, 1961-1964; 16 folders (Box 6)
    - Dividends (Box 6)
    - Shareholders, 1953-1957; 6 folders (Box 6)
    - Stock Redemption, 1955; 6 folders
    - General
      - Bond Issue, 1955 (Box 7)
      - Government Property at Niskayuna-Tank Test Facility (Box 7)
      - Labor-Management Community Services Fund (Box 7)
      - Miscellaneous, 3 folders (Box 7)
      - New York Stock Exchange (Box 7)
      - Promotional Bulletins (Box 7)
      - Reserve Accounts Analysis, 1916-1921 (Box 7)
      - Schenectady - Auburn, 1961 (Box 7)
      - Security Analysts (Box 7)
    - Executives
      - Howard Fogg, 3 folders (Box 7)
      - F. R. Gruger, Jr. (Box 7)
      - George F. Willison (Box 7)
    - Other Companies
      - Flannery Bolt Company, 1936 (Box 7)
      - General Electric Company, 1953; 2 folders (Box 7)
      - McIntosh and Seymour
        - Balance Sheets (Box 7)
        - Engines (Box 7)
        - General Expenses (Box 7)
        - Correspondence, 1925 (Box 7)
        - [General], 1929 (Box 7)
        - Annual Report, 1930 (Box 7)
        - Assets, 1930 (Box 7)
        - General, 1931 (Box 7)
        - Notes Receivable, 1931 (Box 7)
        - Pending, 1931 (Box 7)
        - Profit and Loss, 1931 (Box 7)
      - Montreal Locomotive Works, 2 folders (Box 7)
      - Worthington Corporation, 1964; 3 folders (Box 7)
  - General
    - Accounts, 1959 (Box 8)
    - Air Coolers-Beaumont (Box 8)
    - Albany Industrial Club, 1965 (Box 8)
    - Alco Marine Experience (Box 8)
    - American Management Association (Box 8)
    - American Society of Mechanical Engineers (Box 8)
    - Announcements (Box 8)
    - Anti-Trust Suit, 1963 (Box 8)
    - Appel, Walter (Box 8)
    - Army (Box 8)
    - "At the Old A - L - C - O" Rally Song (Box 8)
    - Auburn Plant Tour (Box 8)
    - Backlog Reports, 1960 (Box 8)
    - John G. Broady Matter (Box 8)
    - Budget, 1961; 2 folders (Box 8)
    - Bureau of Ships (Box 8)
    - Ceramic Coatings (Box 8)
    - Chamber of Commerce (Box 8)
    - Circular letters (Box 8)
    - Civil War Centennial Commission (Box 8)
    - Clips, speeches, circa 1947-1969 (Box 8)
    - Computers (Box 8)
    - Corporate Emergency Advisory Committee (Box 8)
    - Correspondence, 2 folders (Box 8)
    - Costs (Box 8)
    - Crankshafts (Box 8)
    - Cryogenics (Box 8)
    - C.C. Davis (Box 8)
    - Diesel Hydraulic Locomotives (Box 8)
    - Directors and Officers (Box 8)
    - Dunkirk Letterhead (Box 8)
    - Dyna-Soar (Box 8)
    - Eastman Kodak Company, X-Omat Film Processor (Box 8)
    - Electrical Equipment (Box 8)
    - European Community (Box 8)
    - European Trip (Box 8)
    - Exchangers-Heat (Box 8)
    - Extra Copies, 2 folders (Box 8)
    - Feedwater Heaters (Box 8)
    - Flood Control Procedure (Box 8)
    - Fuel - Alco Diesel Fuel Research (Box 8)
    - Fuel - Low Grade Dual Fuel (Box 8)
    - Gas Turbines (Box 9)
    - Gears, 2 folders (Box 9)
    - General, 4 folders (Box 9)
    - Graubart and Tichenor, 1960 (Box 9)
    - Heidrick and Struggles, Inc. (Box 9)
    - Invitation Cards (Box 9)
    - Jersey Central (Box 9)
    - Labels - ALCO (Box 9)
    - Labor Situation, 1957 (Box 9)
    - Locomotives, Miscellaneous (diesels), 1960 (Box 9)
    - Locomotive Orders (Box 9)
    - McQueen, Walter (Box 9)
    - Memoranda, 1947 (Box 9)
    - Miscellaneous (Box 9)
    - New York Giants Training Sleds (Box 9)
    - Piece work schedules, 1907; 1910,; undated; Schenectady Works, general (Box 9)
    - Press Luncheon, 1967 (Box 9)
    - Pritchard, J.F. and Company (Box 9)
    - Program Notices (Box 9)
    - Prospects (Box 9)
    - Railroad Booklet (Box 9)
    - Railway Progress Institute (Box 9)
    - Records Retention (Box 9)
    - Real Estate (Box 9)
    - Riedingers (Box 9)
    - Rogers Locomotive Works, 1917 (Box 9)
    - Sales Reports, 1960; Beaumont, Dunkirk; 2 folders (Box 9)
    - Schedule Meeting, 1960 (Box 10)
    - Screening Couuuittee, 1959-1960 (Box 10)
    - Sears Library of Free Enterprise, 1961 (Box 10)
    - Sleeve Bearings in Reciprocating Engines, 1 volume (Box 10)
    - Society of Naval Architects and Marine Engineers, 1960 (Box 10)
    - Spectrographic Symposium, 1953; 2 vols. (Box 10)
    - Stationary and Marine (Box 10)
    - Stationery (Box 10)
    - Tank Program Report (Box 10)
    - Technical Publications, 1959-1967; corresp. etc re. sale of publications; 6 folders (Box 10)
    - Train of Tomorrow (Box 10)
    - Union Pacific Railroad (Box 10)
    - Visitors-Assistant Secretary of the Army, 1956 (Box 10)
    - Weekly Lab Report, 1960 (Box 10)
    - Worthington Annual Meeting-Schenectady, 1966 (Box 10)
    - Worthington Corporation (Box 10)
    - Year-end and Outlook, 1965 (Box 10)
  - Historical
    - Alco Products, 1 volume (Box 10)
    - Heat Transfer Products, 1 volume (Box 10)
    - Alco, 3 folders (Box 10)
    - Alco - Plymouth Locomotive, 1964 (Box 10)
    - Alco Predecessor Companies (Box 10)
    - Background Sheets (Box 10)
    - Auburn, 5 folders, 1 volume (Box 10)
    - Beaumont, 2 folders (Box 11)
    - Chicago Heights, 2 folders (Box 11)
    - Dunkirk, 2 folders (Box 11)
    - Latrobe, 2 folders, 2 vols. (Box 11)
    - Richmond, Virginia (Box 11)
    - Schenectady, 6 folders (Box 11)
    - Tank History (Box 11)
    - Time Capsule, 1965 (Box 11)
    - Worthington – Alco (Box 11)
    - Worthington Corporate History (Box 11)
  - International
    - Publicity (Box 11)
    - Statistics (Box 11)
    - Translations (Box 11)
    - Australia, 1961; 1962; 2 folders
    - Chile, 1962 (Box 11)
    - Columbia, 1962 (Box 11)
    - Davey Paxman & Co., Ltd., 1961 (Box 11)
    - Equadoz, 1961 (Box 11)
    - Euskalduna, Spain, 1961; 2 folders (Box 11)
    - Euskalduna, Spain, 1962; 2 folders (Box 12)
    - Far East, 1959-1961 (Box 12)
    - France, 1960-1962 (Box 12)
    - Greece, 1962 (Box 12)
    - Honduras, 1961-1962 (Box 12)
    - India, 1962 (Box 12)
    - Liberia, 1961 (Box 12)
    - Mexico, 1961; 2 folders (Box 12)
    - Norway, 1960 (Box 12)
    - Pakistan, 1962 (Box 12)
    - Peru, 1962; 2 folders (Box 12)
    - Renfe, Spain, 1962 (Box 12)
    - Sudan Railways, 1960-1962 (Box 12)
    - Venezuela, 1957 (Box 12)
  - Locomotives
    - Financial, 1962; 12 folders (Box 12)
    - Engines, 1962; 9 folders (Box 12)
    - Labor-Steelworkers' Contract, 1963; 2 folders (Box 12)
    - Locomotives, Domestic, 1962-1963; news releases re orders of new locomotives from1 the following companies
      - Apache Railway (Box 12)
      - Delaware & Hudson Railroad (Box 12)
      - Locomotive Rebuild Program (Box 12)
      - New York Central (Box 12)
      - North Western, Chicago (Box 12)
      - Pennsylvania Railroad, 2 folders (Box 12)
      - Shipments (Box 12)
      - Tape-Controlled Automatic Equipment (Box 12)
      - Tugboat Fleet (Box 12)
    - Locomotives, Foreign
      - Chile (Box 13)
      - Cocoon Packaging-Greece, 3 folders (Box 13)
      - Export Shipment, 1963 (Box 13)
      - Greece, 1962; 2 folders (Box 13)
      - India, 1962; 5 folders (Box 13)
      - International Railway Journal, 1962 (Box 13)
      - Locomotive Exports, 1963 (Box 13)
      - Mexico, 2 folders (Box 13)
      - Overseas Locomotive Maintenance (Box 13)
      - Overseas Orders (Box 13)
      - Overseas Shipments (Box 13)
      - Pakistan, 2 folders (Box 13)
      - Peru-Andes Mountains (Box 13)
      - Sa1es, Export (Box 13)
      - Sydney – Melbourne (Box 13)
    - Personnel, 1962
      - Appointments (Box 13)
      - Bolte (Box 13)
      - Chamberlain (Box 13)
      - Chief Executive (Box 13)
      - Davis (Box 13)
      - Egbert (Box 13)
      - Flug, 2 folders (Box 13)
      - Hardner (Box 13)
      - Industrial Engineers (Box 13)
      - Lawrence (Box 13)
      - Lifset (Box 13)
      - Miller (Box 13)
      - Press - Friedman Wedding (Box 13)
      - Renewal Parts Team (Box 13)
      - Safety Meeting (Box 13)
      - Strobell (Box 13)
      - Sundberg (Box 13)
      - Vaughan (Box 13)
      - Wall Street Journal Interview (Box 13)
    - Plant Closing - Alco Sells Beaumont Operations, 1962 (Box 13)
    - General, 1962
      - Alco Products - Background Summary (Box 13)
      - Behind the Scenes (Box 13)
      - Business Week (Box 13)
      - Depreciation Guidelines and Rules (Box 13)
      - Financial Fillers (Box 13)
      - General Motors Anti-Trust Suit (Box 13)
      - Korfund Dynamics Corporation (Box 13)
      - Long Island Railroad - World's Fair Project (Box 13)
      - Parade of Business (Box 13)
      - People and Spots in the News (Box 13)
      - Poor's Digest (Box 13)
      - Precise Power - Anti-Missile Battery (Box 13)
      - Progress Report (Box 13)
      - Railroad Booklet Letters (Box 13)
      - Railroad Legislation (Box 13)
      - Senator Jacob Javits (Box 13)
      - Steel Magazine Cover (Box 13)
      - Thank-you Notes (Box 13)
      - Worthington Corporation (Box 13)
  - Maps
    - Map Album, 1914; 1 volume (Box 13)
    - Schenectady, before 1872 (Box 13)
    - Schenectady, 1879-1946 (Box 13)
      Years are: 1879, 1884, 1888, 1898, 1906, 1914, 1916, 1918, 1919, 1920, 1922, 1923, 1924, 1925, 1926, 1932, 1934, 1938, 1939, 1941, 1942, 1945 (2 folders), 1946
    - Schenectady, 1953-1959 (Box 14)
    - Schenectady, 1962-1966 (Box 14)
  - News Clippings
    - Alco in the News, 1966 (Box 14)
    - Associated Electric Industries (Box 14)
    - Beaumont Plant Sold, 1962 (Box 14)
    - Davey-Paxman Agreement (Box 14)
    - Diesel Engines, 1964 (Box 14)
    - Dunkirk Plant Sale, 7 folders (Box 14)
    - Export Award Flag (Box 14)
    - Financial
      - Alco Dividend, 2 folders (Box 14)
      - Annual Meeting, 1962 (Box 14)
      - Quarterly Reports, 1962; 5 folders (Box 14)
    - Locomotives
      - Alco-India Pact, 1962; 3 folders (Box 15)
      - Century Series (Box 15)
      - Cocoon – Spray - Plastic Locomotive Shell, 5 folders (Box 15)
      - DL-640 Locomotive (Box 15)
      - Locomotive Paint Scheme (Box 15)
      - Locomotives, 3 folders (Box 15)
      - Workers Sign Locomotive "Greeting Card" to Pakistan, 14 folders (Box 15)
    - Miscellaneous (Box 15)
    - P.T. Egbert Retires (Box 15)
    - Schenectady, 1888 (Box 15)
    - Schenectady Research Laboratory, 2 folders (Box 15)
    - Steel Price-Fixing Indictment (Box 15)
    - Strikes: Auburn, Dunkirk, and Schenectady, 1960 (Box 16)
    - Worthington Purchases Heat Exchanger (Box 16)
  - News Releases
    - Administration
      - Appointments, 2 folders (Box 16)
      - Division Operations (Box 16)
      - Locomotive and Engine Division (Box 16)
      - Marketing (Box 16)
      - Retirements (Box 16)
      - Arthur (Box 16)
      - Ballou (Box 16)
      - Banchiere (Box 16)
      - Boat (Box 16)
      - Bolte, 4 folders (Box 16)
      - Bosworth, 3 folders (Box 16)
      - Brittell (Box 16)
      - Brouthers (Box 16)
      - Burns (Box 16)
      - Byrne, 2 folders (Box 16)
      - Callison, 2 folders (Box 16)
      - Cargile (Box 16)
      - Chamberlain (Box 16)
      - C1ark (Box 16)
      - Daniels (Box 16)
      - Davis, 6 folders (Box 16)
      - Dennis, 2 folders (Box 16)
      - Donahue (Box 16)
      - Eger (Box 16)
      - Ettington, 3 folders (Box 16)
      - Flug (Box 16)
      - Fryar, 2 folders (Box 16)
      - Griffith (Box 16)
      - Guz, 2 folders (Box 16)
      - Habach (Box 16)
      - Hastie, 2 folders (Box 16)
      - Jaeckel (Box 16)
      - Kaiser, 2 folders (Box 16)
      - Kaufmann (Box 16)
      - Klose (Box 16)
      - Lathrop (Box 16)
      - Lawrance (Box 16)
      - Layton (Box 16)
      - Lewis, 3 folders (Box 16)
      - Lifset, 3 folders (Box 16)
      - McQueen (Box 16)
      - Meyl (Box 16)
      - Miller, 6 folders (Box 16)
      - Muller (Box 16)
      - Obrist (Box 16)
      - O'Rourke (Box 16)
      - Press (Box 16)
      - Sheehy, 3 folders (Box 16)
      - Shepler (Box 16)
      - Short (Box 16)
      - Silvis (Box 16)
      - Slater (Box 16)
      - Strassler (Box 16)
      - Strobell, 2 folders (Box 16)
      - Webster (Box 16)
      - Witherell (Box 16)
      - Zimmons, 2 folders (Box 16)
    - Business
      - American Forge and Manufacturing Company (Box 16)
      - Association of Electrical Industries (Box 16)
      - Chicago Heights (Box 16)
      - Davey, Paxman and Company (Box 16)
      - Export Award (Box 16)
      - Hawkridge Brothers (Box 16)
      - International Operations (Box 16)
      - Dave McDonald's Flub (Box 16)
      - New York Alco Office Move (Box 16)
      - Outlook, 1962 (Box 16)
      - Power and Process Equipment (Box 16)
      - Security Analysts (Box 16)
      - Substitutions and Deviations (Box 16)
      - Year-end Statement, 1964 (Box 16)
    - Community Relations
      - Speeches, 3 folders (Box 16)
      - Union College Scholarship (Box 16)
    - Employee Relations
      - General (Box 16)
      - Motive Power (Box 16)
      - Open House, 1966 (Box 16)
      - Rehabilitation (Box 16)
      - United Steel Workers Contract (Box 16)
      - Vacations (Box 16)
    - Facilities
      - Cold-Wound Spring Plant, 1960; 2 folders (Box 16)
      - Electronic Computer Center, 1961; 3 folders (Box 16)
      - Industrial Safety Conference (Box 16)
      - Kwajalein Tracking Station (Box 16)
      - Locomotive Production Center (Box 16)
      - Mediterranean (Box 16)
      - North Bergen (Box 16)
      - Renewal Parts Team (Box 16)
      - Schenectady (Box 16)
      - Spring & Forge Division (Box 16)
      - Varanasi (Box 17)
    - Finance-Quarterly Report, 1963 (Box 17)
    - Products
      - Alatna (Box 17)
      - Alco-Plymouth Locomotive (Box 17)
      - Algerian Pipeline (Box 17)
      - Caltex Diesel Engine (Box 17)
      - Curtis Bay Tug (Box 17)
      - Diesel Engines (Box 17)
      - Diesel-Fuel Filter (Box 17)
      - Diesel Installations-Radar Station (Box 17)
      - Jeffersonville Boat Diesel Engine (Box 17)
      - Lukens Steel (Box 17)
      - Research & Development (Box 17)
      - Sahara Pumping Operations (Box 17)
      - Sixteen-Cylinder Engines-Tankers (Box 17)
      - Skid-Mounted Diesel Generators, Air Force (Box 17)
      - Standards In Action (Box 17)
    - Worthington
      - Alco Becomes Subsidiary of Worthington, 1964 (Box 17)
      - Anniversary (Box 17)
      - Annual Report, 1965 (Box 17)
      - Annual Report, 1966 (Box 17)
      - Annual Meeting-Schenectady, 1966; 3 folders (Box 17)
      - Dividend Increase, 1967 (Box 17)
      - Earnings Increase, 1966; 7 folders (Box 17)
      - Marine Equipment (Box 17)
      - A Report to Henry (Box 17)
      - Stockholders Vote 2-for-1 Split, 1965 (Box 17)
      - Strikes, 1965 (Box 17)
      - Unitron (Box 17)
      - Worthington-Alco (Box 17)
      - Worthington Executive to Address Rotary Club, 1966 (Box 17)
    - Miscellaneous
      - General, undated, 2 folders, 1 volume (Box 17)
      - General, 1956-1962; 5 folders (Box 17)
      - General, 1960-1965; 10 folders (Box 18)
  - Nuclear Energy
    - General
      - Atom-Powered Locomotive (Box 18)
      - Atomic Energy, 1959 (Box 18)
      - Atomic Energy Commission Contract, 1961 (Box 18)
      - Atomic Plant, 2 folders (Box 18)
      - Atomic Power (Box 18)
      - Bilateral Agreement Cleanliness, 1960 (Box 18)
      - Costs, 1958-1960 (Box 18)
      - How Alco Nuclear Capability Can Serve You, 1960 (Box 18)